#### JOÃO PAULO CERCAL Berlin, Germany

linkedin.com/in/jpcercal github.com/jpcercal

#### About me

I've been working with PHP since 2009, I'm a Zend Certified PHP Engineer working with Agile, always looking for best practices and methodologies in order to improve my workflow and so bring great results to the project and to all stakeholders. A developer that likes writing tests, enjoys reading new design-patterns, loves code "well written" (a balance is always essential), and reads about 20 books per year. =)

### Experience

GetYourGuide

### Senior Software Engineer

Currently

- Impacting and changing the way how millions of travellers connect to the places they visit, in combination with rigorous A/B testing to craft an unbeatable e-commerce. In numbers during the last months my team created about 20 experiments and I worked with 4 of them, in which the last one that I've worked on increased the conversion rate in almost 2%;
- Aligning the product with technical decisions while having the customer at first and considering data over guessing have guided me to influence in a killer feature to contact us through whatsapp in which our customers can get support from their smartphones. It increased the second customer purchase metric considerably and helped us to retain customers;
- Doing interviews, providing long detailed feedback right after interviews about talents while suggesting improvements to the overal process in order to hire the best talents and so develop a really good product;
- Test driven oriented, impacting the way that the company sees test bringing then, the quality of the product to the next level.

FlixBus Senior PHP Developer 2017 - 2018

- Changing the life of approximately one billion of people commuting, spending their weekends, building remote relationships, visiting relatives, and discovering the world;
- We improved the response time for retrieving a cart in almost 70% by extracting the code from the monolith to a new microservice-oriented architecture;
- Volunteer to be a facilitator in agile ceremonies such as retrospective and spring review;
- Responsible for taking decisions from a technical perspective regarding our domain.

NeoGrid Senior PHP Developer 2015 - 2017

- Created a web application using Material Design and AngularJS to the front-end and Silex to the back-end, which automated the sales of the WebEDI solution;
- Implemented improvements, bug fixes and integrations with NeoGrid solutions using REST APIs;
- Added the Vagrant tool to use with my team in order to use environments identical with the production environment;
- Evangelist of best practices of programming following the existent PSRs and implementing unit test in the projects;
- Reference in my team to projects that was written in PHP and AngularJS.

Humantech PHP Developer 2015 - 2015

- Led the team (five workers) as assistant manager of the programming department when the manager was not present;
- Added unit tests in critical project parts, reducing considerable the amount of bugs and increasing the quality of projects;
- Created an e-learning platform using the gamification concepts.

A2C PHP Developer 2013 - 2014

- Created a CMS to the 3M brand using the gamification concepts and fully focused on SEO, that resulted in three times more
  access to the website in few months;
- Created a software to monitor the reputation of political candidates in social networks, that give more visibility on medias to the agency;
- Reference in my team to projects that was written in Symfony 2;
- Responsible to manage the Amazon Web Services EC2, RDS and S3.

## Education

# UNISOCIESC BSc Information Systems

2011 - 2014

- Honor as the best student of the course;
- The final paper is based on a tool created to be used by professionals that are studying to achieve the ZCPE certification, the project is open-source and is available on GitHub, the project is hosted by "DigitalOcean" as a sponsor.